[Music]
hey welcome to connecting with code 2020
we're so glad you made it
this is our first video there's gonna be
five of these videos so each day Monday
Tuesday Wednesday Thursday Friday
there's gonna be a video follow along
with me and what's gonna happen is I'm
doing these videos live with some
campers as you might guess I'm in my
home
so my campers are my family but I'm
going to use this camera so that you can
meet my campers
so our first camper would you like to
introduce yourself and say hello your
age a that's great
and so Keegan is going to be working by
himself today as age 8 he's a perfect
age for this camp our next set of
campers and he's age 6 and since Bowen
is age 6 he's gonna need a little bit of
help this is adult helper want to
introduce yourself yeah oh and by the
way you'll notice that mom and Keegan
are both wearing a connecting with coach
shirt very nice and then we've got one
more camper with us because I see my son
up there
so we're last camper you want to
introduce yourself finally can you share
any paged
she's H Tim and so McKinley has actually
coded for quite a while
and she might be a little advanced for
this material but she is gonna have fun
Jordans raices all right so those are my
campers and everybody is kind of ready
to go today and what I want you to do is
I want you to start off by going over to
tinker tinker is Tyn keer hopefully
you've been there from the email you got
through before and you've been able to
get signed in so you're gonna sign in as
a student and your username and password
should kind of be in the format CWC 2020
and then your name of your camper
whatever name you provided so here it's
David Fisher now
once you sign in you can see a couple
things you can see your dashboard and
your dashboard has all these ticker
coding challenges that you can work all
on your own so there's quite a few of
them that we've set up ideally you've
spent some time trying these things like
dragons spell or Barbie you can be
anything they are really well made and
you should definitely spend some time
doing it in camp we spend 20 minutes
every day doing these before we start on
like the project for that day so
definitely be aware of that but for the
videos that you do with B we're not
going to do those because you can do
those in your own we're going to be down
into my projects area I'm and then the
my projects area you probably have no
projects right now so it's probably
completely empty I've got two because I
had to practice for today and so what
we're going to do is we're going to make
a project but what I'm going to do is
I'm going to show you the finished
solution first and so at the end of this
video this is what you're going to be
able to create right so here is a
finished solution so I'm going to go
ahead and show you the game it's a it's
a pretty simple game the way this game
works is I have a one actor he's a
monster and his job is to collect
cupcakes so he likes to eat cupcakes and
so he collected this cupcake and you'll
actually notice that maybe he's going a
little faster
and every time he collects a cupcake he
gets closer and closer to winning and of
course I've made a couple versions of
this game but you can see that this is
this is the game that we're making
another thing that I wanted to show that
I forgot to show in the last what's all
I'll do a better job of saying it here
is there's a counter up in the corner
and it's counting keeping track room
variable you can make your counter go up
or down here this one's going down and
then whenever you get all the way to the
bottom eyes as you win so let's start
doing some of these things so go ahead
and go to your project area and click on
create a new project whenever you create
a new project there's a couple of
templates that you can choose from you
can click on either
blank project or blank block cluding
project I'm pretty sure that they're the
same but I'm going to choose to click on
blank block coding project just because
that's specifically what we're doing so
now it's kind of brought you into the
world of tinker tinker projects are very
very similar to scratch projects if
you're familiar with that and the way
that they work is that you have your
stage so this is my stage area over here
on your stage you have different actors
scratch columns sprite but here we call
it actors and your actors have different
code that they do right and so this
project even the blank project gave you
a little code and what we can do is we
can go through and we can look at what
this code does and then we also have a
tool box over here where we can add more
code let's start off by running our
project and seeing what our code does
right now what our code does right now
is sorry when we hit play down here on
the right you can see my code started
playing you can always stop your code
for play or start your code playing
you'll notice that once your code starts
playing your actor starts moving and you
get this green outline around your code
saying hey this code is happening let's
look at this code this code says onstart
so that's an event which means when the
game starts and so anything that's
connected below that is going to happen
where the game starts the first thing
that we do after onstart is a little
setup we do an advanced thing it's
called sent rotation style left right so
our monster he only goes left and right
learn those rights there that affects
his image and then this is interesting
we're telling him to do something
forever so forever do these things now
if I were to ask poet I say Bowen you'll
brush your teeth forever I'd be pretty
beat right yeah you wouldn't do that to
a person
but with code saying to do something
forever is just fine
in fact we do it all the time and the
thing that this monster does forever is
he animates his walk so you'll notice
that he's kind of got this animated
he's moving 10 pixels so that's kind of
how far he moves if he's on an edge
bounce and then wait 0.05 seconds that
so he doesn't go too fast and the fun
thing about code is you can take pieces
out of the code and see how it changes
the behavior in tinker there's two
handles on every block code there's a
left handle and a right handle left
handle selects that code and everything
below it right handle selects just that
line so try this
grab animate walk grab the handle on the
right and take it out of your code now
what happens is your code runs without
that command in it so you can see that
my monster is still going back and forth
it's just not walking anymore it just is
animation for walking just happening and
that's because that command isn't in
there if I put it back in
then I'll of course begin his little
walking animation you can try this with
other pieces of your code as well let's
say that instead of moving at a speed of
10 pixels he moved at a speed of 100
pixels and so now if we run it at 100
pixels you can see he goes back and
forth very fast and so this project
started with a little bit of code in it
but I actually want to practice writing
some of these things so what I'm going
to do is I'm going to take a fair amount
of this code out just just for the sake
of practice I want the heck let's just
go ahead and write it all together and
get it'll be fun
the nice thing about writing it all
together again is that if you would like
this is an advanced thing if people are
Vance let's say you don't like the
monster and you wanted to pick a
different character you could if you
wanted you don't have to do this you can
click on add actor and add a different
actor I'm gonna stick with my monster
because I think that'll be easier if you
did add something different then you can
delete your monster totally up to you
right so let's start adding our code for
our monster now we're gonna repeat some
of the things that we saw because we're
just getting started about learning how
to do this and so we're gonna start
building our monster back up
the first thing we have to do in our
code is we have to say on start this is
a very very very popular way to start
your coding projects because this is
when you click start this code runs in
scratch if you have to jump scratch this
is somewhere to win green flag clicked
right alright the next thing that was in
here which is not in here anymore
was a blue command that set his rotation
style that was kind of an advanced
command but let's see if we can find it
in our list of commands the way commands
are broken up is they're broken up by
color by category for what they do and
so if you can think about what type of
command is this you could probably find
its category pretty quickly or maybe
you're good at remembering what color
things are that command which was a
sneaky command was a dark blue and it
was called set rotation style so what
you have to do is you have to click on
the motion category inside the motion
category you have to look around until
you find the command you want and then
you drag it over and then you connect it
on to the bottom of one start now you'll
notice that whenever you connect things
they kind of snap into place but you
have to make sure that that snap happens
to get it all all so now I'm not too
worried about what this command does
we're just kind of practicing some of
these things and most commands so this
is set rotation style have these boxes
of them now click on this word all
around if you remember the code we
deleted that the code we deleted said
hey make his image to working a term
right and left but always keep his feet
at the bottom so his image can turn
right and left but his feet stay at the
bottom that's exactly what we want by
the way the code that we're writing here
is with blocks just like how scratch
worked but interestingly real software
developers they do these same things
they just type it right and the
advantage of blocks is you can just drag
and drop it over if you wanted to see
though the actual code that's happening
here there's this little button that the
JN and s you don't have to click on this
just watch this stands for JavaScript
and this will show you the code that
you're actually writing which is
JavaScript we won't look at here very
often but I'm going to
back to the blocks right now the next
thing I want to do is I want to say hey
monster I want you to do something
forever so I need to find a forever loop
a forever loop is a type of control
things that are in the control category
are like you know forever loops if
statements for loops that repeats a
number of times but see if you can find
the command that says forever there it
is
so take forever and lock it on here so
once he starts he's going to send us
your rotation style one time and then
inside of here are going to be commands
that happen forever so what I want him
to do forever is actually something
different than what he did before before
he walked back and forth in a straight
line but what I want him to do now is I
want him to point towards my mouse
pointer I said wherever my mouse pointer
is I want him to point there and then I
want him to move in that direction so
let's do this these are motions so go to
motion and I want to find a command
called point towards mouse pointer so
there's two that are kind of similar
there's go-to mouse pointer that is not
the one we want and then there's the one
that we do want down here at the bottom
point towards mouse pointer now these
commands are different one just makes
him like point at it and then the other
like zooms in there immediately I don't
want to zoom in there so I just I was
just porting that one out for what not
to do right so I want to point towards
the mouse pointer now interestingly if
you hit play in your program right now
it kind of feels like he's not really
working right because he will point left
and right but he doesn't move right so
like if my mouse is over here he sees my
mouse is over here and he points towards
the mouse now he's just doing left and
right because that's what we told him to
do not like spinning all around but he's
not moving
because we haven't written the commands
for movement yet so we have to write
some commands for movement so if we want
him to move we have to write code
to do that so inside movements at the
very top fine move 10 pixels now the
speed that something moves is a is a
function of two things it's how far do
you move and how long do you wait like
after that move so its speed is actually
distance divided by time but I gotta go
there so we're gonna move ten pixels and
then we're gonna wait for a short period
of time
otherwise it's gonna go too fast right a
weight is a type of control so a weight
is in the control area and fine where it
says wait one second and we're gonna
drag it and drop it into here now
waiting for one second actually makes my
game go too slow if I were to run it
right now he would it would work he
would he would move towards my cursor
it's just really slow and it would
eventually get kind of boring to watch
him move at a snail's pace
I think I'm bored now and so what I want
to do is I want to make him go faster
now the speed that I like to use is I
like to use a weight it's kind of a
funny number of 0.05 so you can have
your adult hope you typed if you want
there now what this is is this is one
twentieth of a second and I found that
it's kind of a speed that makes my game
look pretty good right it's also called
twenty frames per second as soon as you
get into games now right now my monster
is going towards my mouse and if it gets
there it kind of freaks out I consider
that a feature just going to leave that
feature in there and if he gets that it
kind of freaks out but what I do want to
do is I want to make him look like he's
walking right so I want him to look like
he's walking now this character there's
two ways you can do that this character
has looks or where you could change his
costume he also has animations that you
could run I'm going to choose
to use the animation this time and I'm
going to choose which animation I'd like
for him to do
I could choose for him to run it so now
he looks like he's running or I could
choose for him to walk it just depends
on what speed you kind of feel like your
monsters going at it doesn't really
matter what you choose also it's fun to
just look at different things let's just
kind of look at like his bite animation
there's have these things you could do
there right now I'm gonna leave it as
walked but I don't mind if you make your
games different than mine right it said
your monster I'm gonna leave mine as
walk or run doesn't matter but if you
wanted to use something different that's
fine with me now if you pick the
different type of actor let's say you
switched your monster you may not have
any animations and if that's the case
that's fine right alright so I think my
monster is doing pretty good so now I'm
gonna do one of the most important
things in software development does
anybody know what one of the most
important things in software development
is McKinley I'm gonna save my work I've
been typing forever but I'm gonna save
it now so up here at the top where it
says untitled I want you to type in the
title of this project will be I think a
good name is monster feast but again if
you want to call you something different
like maybe bow it will say Bowens a
monster feast or McKinley wants to say I
don't know McKinley's dinner
you can do whatever you want and then
you can click on save when you click on
save it's gonna ask you do you want to
just save it which is like local to be
or do you want to save and publish it
and publish means other people could see
it right now I'm just gonna click Save
you can also put in a description here
if you wanted you don't have to do this
at all right connecting with code day
one this is officially the week one camp
so I'm gonna click on save all right so
the next thing I want to do is right now
my monster is walking around
quickly white stage I think that we
could do better than white and so what
we want to do is we want to have him
walk around some background some
environment now the background is called
the stage so you notice that right now
you can click on stage or you can click
on actor when you click on the stage all
your code goes away that's not really
scary because it's actually just odd the
actor amount the stage by the way you
can also change the name of this guy he
is an actor and his name is actor that's
kind of a silly name for an actor it's
kind of like if you had a baby and you
decided to name your baby if you decided
how I'd be good name oh how about human
right this is my human date human all
right so I'm gonna change his name
instead of actor I'm gonna call him
monster now on the stage right now we
don't have any costumes so there's no
Edit pencil there's only a gear click on
this year after you click on that gear
you'll notice that there's things you
can do in sounds advanced or costumes we
want to add a background and what you
can do is you can pick a category and
then select the background that you
think would look good for you you could
pick any background you like I think
that Maya know it came from cookie gets
right here the kitchen so I'm gonna say
kitchen now I can add more backgrounds
if I wanted but I just need one
background something hit the X and so
now my game so I can walk around has a
kitchen just got a tea now what I want
to do in this kitchen is I want to
collect food so I'm gonna go around I'm
going to collect food and I'm gonna eat
it and then once I've collected enough
food it's gonna say you win now there's
no way to lose this game because it's
our first game I've done get more
complex don't worry but what we need to
do is we need to add another actor
that's got to be our food that we
collect so go and click on add actor
whenever you add an actor you could draw
it you could use one of their special
characters or you could use the media
library or you can upload your own write
some fun things there I'm gonna say
media library and what I'm gonna do is
I'm going to go looking around for
good image that might be fun for my
monster to eat I think cooking has a lot
of good things to eat
I could add like a cake or candy canes
or chocolate or whatever you'd like I
think when I find the most delicious are
cupcakes so I'm going to click on so now
I have a stage a monster and a cupcake
now I'm gonna rename my cupcake cupcake
waddlin now you'll see you later
whatever we have multiple cupcakes why I
named him cupcake one but it's cuz I'm
gonna have a 1 2 3 4 5 things you get
the idea and my cupcake has no code so
he's completely blank my monster eyes
code but my cupcake has done you'll also
notice that my cupcake is huge right if
your image came in huge what you can do
is you can grab a handle and you can put
it where you want and you can make it
the size you want maybe that's a good
sized cupcake for our monster I'm gonna
set it right up here on the table by the
way other things you can do is scratch
or take her just so you know is you can
click on there's like a tab up here at
the bot at the top you can see your
stage bigger that's not really that
useful if you're on a computer but if
you're on like an iPad that button is
very useful but you can also make your
stage bigger by clicking on this little
like expand everywhere and it makes it
bigger but just make sure you make it
smaller at some point all right so I've
got my cupcake sized about where I
wanted positioned about where I wanted
and I'm gonna start my monster kind of
down here in the corner now what I want
to do is I want to have code on my
cupcake as well so I click on my cupcake
I want to put in an on start for my
cupcake so I go up to events I find the
very first command which is on start and
what I'm gonna do is I'm going to tell
my cupcake to always check if the
monster's touching you so if you listen
to my words here you can figure out what
the code is always needs to do something
forever and check means if
statement.write will get better at these
things so first I go to control I go
it's find that forever
I'm going to say forever check to see if
they're touching a monster and so check
is an if statement so I'm gonna go and
grab the if statement and bring it in
now the if statements that I brought in
it says if false then we're really false
is just a place over it says if this
condition happens then we run this code
that's kind of the idea of how it works
so the condition that I want here is I
wanted it since whether I'm touching the
monster or not and I cheated I said the
key word in there this is a command
that's in the sensing category so click
on the sensing category and what I want
to do is I want to find the command that
says mi touching the monster now it
turns out that there is no command that
says touching monster the one that you
want is touching mouse pointer and
you're like well that's kind of weird
because I don't care about if I'm
touching your mouse pointer I care about
if I'm touching the monster
well this command has one of those boxes
that you can change right and I want to
change this box to say if touching
monster so if I'm touching the monster
then I want to do something the thing I
want to do is I want to hide I want my
cupcake to hide to disappear hide is it
looks so you got to go to the looks
category don't worry you looking good
about switching back and forth between
categories in the side of looks you'll
have to scroll to ear the bottom near
the bottom there's an area called
visibility and I want to do two things
if I touch the monster I want to hide
and now I'll warn you if you were to
play your game right now it would hide
your cupcake and that it would just be
gone forever right so you actually want
to actually show it initially so I added
two things there I added window I want
to show it and window I want to hide it
I want to show it on starters and then
if I'm ever touching the monster that I
want to hide it
now one thing I like to do with code is
I've got enough code here that I could
test it and so what I want to do is my
games not done I know it's not done but
I wouldn't test it and see if I really
do hide I would I touch the monster so
I'm gonna test my code so I'm gonna run
it my lobster is kind of like ambling
all here following my mouse pointer if
he gets to my mouse pointer he does kind
of freak out feature and if he touches
the cupcake the cupcake successfully
hides
now after a hide is kind of like well
one now what I do right well you can
stop your game and you can hit play
again and you can play it again but
there's no way to win your game really
but you can make that cupcake hide which
is good so we'd like to do a good time
to save by the way click on save saving
saved so what we'd like to do is we'd
like to make it to where you can collect
like five cupcakes or some number of
cupcakes and then you win the game hey
also just because it bothers me right
now my cupcake is gone right wait why is
my cupcake gone and it's gone because
the last thing it did was hide and so
what I want to do this is this is a
little trick I'm going to start my game
and stop it almost immediately and that
way the last thing my cupcake did was a
show so now I can kind of see it you
don't have to do that but I like to see
it as I'm doing my development so what I
want to do is I want to keep track of
how many cupcakes Ivy does anybody have
any ideas for how we would keep track of
something
McKinley variables yeah so we want to
keep track of how many what would you do
that we want to keep track of how many
cupcakes we beat so I'm going to go into
a new area called variables inside
variables I'm going to create a variable
so click on create variable you can name
this variable whatever you would like
I'm gonna call it food because I don't
know what you've got maybe you've got
cupcakes maybe we've got something
that's not food who knows what your
monster likes to eat maybe he likes to
eat ten cans
and then you've got it aside this is
kind of an advanced question do I want
this variable for all actors or for this
actor only well all the actors are going
to share this variable so what's called
a global variable everybody shares it so
I want to say food is for all actors
great so create it now I've got this
variable food and I can run my game and
I've got a variable food it's inside my
computer somewhere but I'm not using it
any interesting way I also can't see the
value anywhere right so that I have no
idea what this variable is now they've
got a feature for this because we're
getting started with variables they've
got a feature that lets you see the
variable like see it's either under the
hood here's how you see it it's called a
watcher so click on food and then
there's a new command that pops up
called add watcher I click this button
and then kind of watch what happens I
click this button and what it did it's
kind of sneaky is it added another actor
this actor is a little green box just
kind of weird and this actor doesn't
really like participate in the game he
just shows you the value of the variable
food now he is actually an actor just
like everything else is an actor he has
code just like the mob stress code and
the cupcake has code and this guy has
code and interestingly this is
unfortunate there is a bug in his code
sorry
the auto generated code has a bug in it
yes everyone makes mistakes here's what
you've got to do you've got to find this
bug the bug is where it says property
food of company by the way it's good to
get better at using your tools so you
can zoom way out and you can see like
the whole thing or you can zoom way in
you can also just grab the black area
and kind of like move over this way but
it's good to get better at brew the
route and the bug is kind of silly
property food of cupcake it shouldn't
say cupcake here we should say of any I
could have left you see that bug later
that's a volunteer coup that wasn't even
your fault so let's go back to our
monster now we fixed our little bug and
let's set the variable food and see it
show up up here so to set the variable
food I'm gonna go I'm still variables
I'm gonna take the third command which
is a set and it's the very very first
thing I'm gonna set food to be zero now
you could choose to count up but so this
time I'm going to count up at my other
example I counted down
you can count up or down it's up to you
but I'm gonna start food off a zero and
you'll notice if you look at my stage
that it shows food right there now what
I want to happen is whatever I collect a
cupcake I want food to go up by one so
we can do that so let's go back to our
cupcake so whenever you make a game
you've got all these actors that
interact at the interest place and when
the cupcake hides I want him to also
change that variable so I'm in my
cupcake as I clicked on my cupcake I see
my cupcake code right here and for this
cupcake I'm gonna change the variable so
I'm in variables and I say change by and
I'm gonna put this either right below
hide or right above hide it doesn't
matter as long as it's inside this if
statement somewhere that's all that
really matters but I want to change food
by one now if you would prefer to count
down you could you could say change food
by negative one I'm just gonna count up
I'm gonna keep it simple and so now when
I run it you'll notice that food is zero
and as soon as I grab that cupcake food
change to one pretty cool now I want a
bunch of food probably a good time to
save by the way I'm gonna go and click
on save again but I want a bunch of food
so that I can collect lots of
lots of food and then as soon as I get
like all the food that I know that I'd
want so let's go ahead and make more
cupcakes so the first thing I want to do
all my cupcakes invisible again I know
this trick it's because the last thing
he did was hide if I hit play and stop
then he'll show up then the last thing
he did was show up right now I'm going
to duplicate it so to duplicate it I'm
gonna click on these three dots and
select duplicate and tinkers nice to you
it kind of moves it a little bit but I'm
gonna move it somewhere different and
then I'm gonna select on this one I'm
gonna say duplicate again but I've got
two and you can choose to make as many
as you would like I know there's a
temptation to make like thousand but I
recommend you only make like I don't
know four or five Raziel I also
recommend that you move them somewhere
that isn't like directly in front of
your monster right I saw like I wouldn't
want to put the cupcakes like right here
because then I would start my game and
he would just get that one right so I'm
gonna move them kind of far away from
where he starts at cool so now I've got
five cupcakes now their names were kind
of ridiculous their names are like 11
and 111111 I'm gonna change all those
names just to be 1 2 3 4 5 that is
optional it's just if you if you want to
you could make that happen now let's see
if when we collect a cupcake so there
I've collected one and my variable isn't
one if I collect two my variables at two
and I'm going to keep going until I get
them all three and then four and then
five cool so my game totally worked
I won my game I collected all the
cupcakes but I really don't feel very
satisfied because he's just still
walking away
right so what I would like to do is I
would like to tell my user you know you
win good job and I would like to stop
the game right because the game has been
won so let's see if we can go do those
things so back to your monster so your
monster is kind of like the main
character in your game so code that
that's like important goes on your
monster right and so here's what I want
to do with my monster
I want my monster to always check if
food the variable is equal to five in my
case because I have five pieces of food
so I said check so I know that I needed
if statement so I'm gonna go to control
inside control I've got to add an if
statement it can go wherever you would
like inside your monsters forever loop
I'm gonna put it at the bottom just goes
as well I feel like it and so if some
condition happens then from this code
the condition that we're looking for is
does the variable food equal five so I
got to find what goes into this
condition it's in operators inside
operators look for an equals side the
equal sign it's the second one down in
boolean and you'll notice that if you
look at the equal sign but it's kind of
shaped like a little hexagon diamond
thing and so that is a cue for you that
it goes into a condition like this and
now what I want to say here is I want to
say if food equals five so I've got to
go to variables I've gotta find by food
variable so here's my food variable I'm
gonna drag it into the left hand side if
food equals five
then you've just won and you need to say
you win right so inside the if statement
I want to say you win now interestingly
what we're going to say is we're gonna
say it with
speech bubble you win so that's actually
it looks scroll to the scariest Lincoln
command you can find it looks this one
is super scary so this one that says say
hello and then there's like a - an
applause for two seconds that's the one
you want now we could use one of these
not scary ones like say hub for two
seconds or something like that but the
scary one I actually want all these
options right so yeah we're starting
with the world's scariest man so let's
look at this super scary command a
little bit the most important part is
what he says so right now he says hello
you can decide what you wanted to say I
could hear one of my campers over there
it is says you win
good job mode I'm going to say you win
good job Dave now when you win you've
got all kinds of options in this textbox
you could leave the defaults and just
not worry about it the defaults give you
a bottom message box which I think looks
pretty good if you wanted to leave that
but you could do different things you
could have like your actor could say it
I think it could be like a speech bubble
from your actor you could change the
font you can do about whatever you want
what I'm gonna do not because it matters
is I'm gonna pick a speech bubble or
rectangular speech bubble and I'm gonna
make the font quite a bit bigger I'm
gonna make the font a 48 font so let's
try it so I hit play I start collecting
cupcakes now one thing you might notice
is that your monster is just a little on
the slow side I bet something you can
fix but it totally works it totally
works but it totally has one little
feature I don't like and that's after I
get the last one it worked
it said you win good job Dave but then
the game kind of keeps playing it kind
of an awkward
so the game is over and so what I want
to do and you can choose what you want
to do I want I just want the game to
stop right that's not be enough for me
so after I say you win good job Dave I
want the game to stop
that's it control it's the very last
command and control that says stop all
so stop all we want to put immediately
after that big scary command so say you
would good job Dave and then stop all
now it's very important that this stop
all is inside of the if statement so I
can click on like this handle and I can
see that it is it back inside of it now
you can run yours like that but I'm
going to show you a mistake just to kind
of show it to you let's say that I was
not paying very good attention let's say
that I put my stop all come in right
here you're like oh that looks about the
same it's not and the reason it's not is
because the if statements only has the
say in it
and the stop all is actually just inside
the forever right so it's not inside of
it so now what happens is if I run my
game he just stops immediately right and
it that's what's called a bug they can
be very hard to find there are some
tools and Taker that trying to help you
find bugs it's called this little bug
icon
sometimes that bug icon is useful I can
show you like where things are going
wrong I don't know if I really use that
bug that much but it's there but just
know that everybody makes bugs buttons
are a part of coding and the way we plan
to help you with bugs is we have zoom
meetings so if you go to our camp page
which you hopefully saw the email
there's rules home and students that can
help you with bugs and so if you have a
bug that you need help with rules hoping
students will be at those zoom meetings
to help you out so I'm gonna get my last
one and it says you win good job Dave
so I think that I have a finished game
after I play a game if I want to play
again I just have to hit start and stop
I think that I have a finished game so
I'm going to go ahead and publish mine
so other people can see it there are
some extras that you can add I'll just
kind of mentioned some of those extras
if you'd like to add extras but first
I'm going to go ahead and publish mine
so I'm gonna stick on this down arrow
next to save I'm gonna say publish to
community so this is monsterpiece maybe
I'll call it
Dave's monster feast and I'll say save
and publish now with your games I do
recommend that you add little extras so
for example a little extra here might be
that I could make him go faster than Ted
like maybe I want him to go in 20 or an
even more advanced little extra you
don't have to do this just saying you
couldn't make a variable called speed
and that variable speed you don't have
to do this you just watch it that
variable speed could start off at like
10 and I could use that variable speed
I'm doing this fast for this optional
and then my other cupcakes could change
speed in addition to changing food and
then I would get faster right so maybe
they'll make speed go up so I only put
this on one cupcake but right now my
speed is kind of a slow speed but as
soon as I get that cupcake on I'm going
fast so there's all kinds of extras that
you could add to your game this camp day
there's also if you would like a whole
extra assignment a whole extra video
it's called scorekeeper if you would
like to do extra go watch that video
that's totally fine but keep in mind
that it's not really part of the camp
day it is in fact just an extra so I'm
not gonna have my campers join me for
that I'm just gonna give extra thanks
for the people to watch now the main
thing that I want to do today is I want
to see how my campers did so I've got
Keegan here
so keep my campers like to do things
that are different
he didn't chose to use a spin of a
monster he used the cobbler these guns
have done a little bit before right and
he's collecting things in a graveyard
and as soon as he gets to 10 it says you
went
good job Keegan hey buddy that is
awesome did you crush it today
all right let's go check out how poet
did today but how much help did you have
to have some balm today little that's
great so so the goal camp for adults is
to try to let them control the mouse as
much as you could possibly handle all
right so let's look at bones today so
starting from beginning boat hits top
story dinner any Bowen is collecting
gold coins and the way says you win good
job Bowen that's awesome buddy hey did
you have a fun time making that today
did you do a good job at learn a whole
bunch he's got a great job Bowen six
great job oh all right now our ringer
McKinley did you successfully make a
game today
so McKinley is a little bit older and so
she oh she made any bitty apples I see
them now so there's one way down there
that was awesome
all right campers did you enjoy your
first day I can't yeah are you gonna
come back tomorrow are you gonna learn a
whole bunch this week yes all right well
we really enjoyed having yep I hope you
enjoy the camp love for people to get a
t-shirt sorry we can't get it to you in
time while you're doing this camp but it
helps like give you a good spirit of
like being in the camp all right thanks
so much for joining us
look forward to seeing you tomorrow bye
[Music]